Jeffrey Brownlow

Data Scientist

Santa Barbara, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jeffrey-Brownlow/2934ecf0d89946ef

I'm an idea person. Anything is possible; everything is negotiable. I love developing unique solutions to complex problems. I am enthusiastic, forward thinking, organized, reserved, imaginative, structured, sociable, warm, logical, innovative, and independent. I'm a powerful workhorse that just needs to be pointed into the right direction. I'll figure it out.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

Intouch Health - March 2017 to June 2017

- A. Developed a staging database for templating reporting needs in DOMO and to develop the engineering required to scale to a fully functioning database using a Postgresql RDS instance in AWS.
- B. Developed ETL jobs in python to extract data from Domo, Kapost, Salesforce, Marketo and Twitter; used the cron scheduler in an AWS EC2 instance to update the staging database every 5 minutes. This included identifying updated records, deleting deleted records, and inserting new records.
- C. Developed the skeleton for customizable reporting in DOMO using Javascript, CSS, and HTML5 allowing for the creation of visualizations and functions not currently accessible in the current BI architecture.
- D. Developed two separate REST APIs for Vidyard to collect viewership data from our video content management
- software. One method used an Flask web service developed in python and deployed to an Elastic Beanstalk instance in AWS. The other used a combination of a Gateway API and Lambda function in AWS. The second API was used because they are inherently secure. The issue between the two was the low volume of viewership. Lambda functions reset after (x) amount of time, and this can cause some POSTs to take longer than expected.
- E. Developed reporting tables that would periodically compare the true values in my staging database to the true

values in our marketing systems to provide a check on data validity. Current method focused on count.

F. Developed logging table that reported the time to complete for each ETL job to it make it easier to detect if any

data quality issues or ETL errors were present.

- G. Managed roughly 40 reports, including drill-downs, in DOMO for twenty users.
- H. Developed reporting tables for users to empower self-reporting for their vertical.
- I. Helped with identifying strengths and weaknesses of other BI tools for our new Customer BI tool initiative.
- J. Prototyped a Salesforce Visualforce page to showcase Salesforce's capabilities and to inspire current

developers to expand on what they believed to be possible.

- K. Managed relationships with IT to help internalize the Marketing architecture with the rest of the business.
- L. Processed all reporting needs accurately and efficiently.
- M. In the process of developing automated reporting procedures to simplify data access to multiple users across marketing verticals for future state adoption; star schema approach.
- N. Researched website clickstream data gathering requirements for Adobe, Google, and Piwik; and the necessary

engineering involved with data capture for each system.

Marketing Data Analyst

American Advisors Group - February 2015 to March 2017

- A. Developed Net Present Value model using regression and logistic regression models to predict revenue at various stages during lead generation and development.
- B. Developed experimental mix media model to determine optimal spend. Findings suggested that we were underspending on our television marketing budget.
- C. Determined the correlation between state license distribution among loan officers and RSVP rates. That aided in optimizing future license distribution so as to limit the number of RSVP leads.
- D. Developed experimental neural network to determine customer segmentation between home owners with large lien amounts and those without. Recall topped out at 65%; determined to be less useful.
- E. Developed correlation model to determine what portion of our television spend was responsible for our paid and organic search lead volume.
- F. Developed a scheduled ETL job in Salesforce to pull marketing content data from our content management system ProofHQ.
- G. Developed customer service scripting tool in salesforce to automate lead distribution and shorten time between calls.
- H. Developed automated RSVP callback scheduler in salesforce to connect to customers at a later date if requested.
- I. Designed a user interface that speed up data acquisition for our direct mail interns.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Applied Statistics

California State University
August 2013 to December 2014

Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry

California State University, Long Beach - Long Beach, CA January 2011 to June 2013

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Python

Pandas, Scikit-Learn, StatsModels, Keras, Theanos, Requests, Rpy2, Matplotlib, Numpy, and Scipy

SQL

Postgresql, Redshift, MySQL, and SQL Server

AWS

EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, Gateway, Lambda, and Security Groups (IAM)

ВΙ

Tableau and Domo

Salesforce

Apex, Visualforce, Scheduler, Batch Processing, Administration, SOQL, and SOSL

Web

HTML5, Javascript, and CSS

Machine Learning Neural Networks, Dimensionality Reduction, Regression, and Classification

Statistics

Experimental Design, Feature Selection, Survival Analysis, and Time Series Analysis